这是二零二二年普通高等学校招生全国统一考试英语科听力部分第一次考试。该部分分为第一、第二两节。注意。回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。现在是听力试音时间。
International Friends Club, can I help you?
Oh, hello. I read about your club in the paper today, and I thought I'd phone to
find out a bit more.
Yes, certainly. Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
Er, what kinds of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
OK. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form and
some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。听力考试正式开始，请看听力部分第一节。第一节。听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题。从题中所给的
three A, B, and Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
三个选项中选出最佳选项。听完每段对话。哦，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题，每段对话仅读一遍。例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷。卷上的例题。你将听到以下内容。
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有。有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷上。衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择项，并将其标在试卷上。现在，你有五秒钟的时间。边阅读第一小题的有关内容。
What type of movies do you like?
I like all sorts of primarily musicals and action movies.
What about you?
I prefer science fiction.
Good morning, Mr.
Rockefeller. Mr. Flint wants to see you on a very urgent business matter.
Send him in, please.
Can you turn the music off?
I can't concentrate on my study.
Sorry, Jane. I thought you had finished your final exam already.
Not until this Thursday.
Hi, Julia. Are you here on holiday?
Yes, it's a beautiful town and it's so sunny here.
So sad it's my last day here.
Hi, Lee. I know you are from Seoul.
I heard there are animal cafes in your city.
Is that true?
Yes. Actually, there is one near my apartment.
I often go there.
It's great fun working on the computer surrounded by lovely animals.
第一节到此结束。第二节，听下面五段对话或独白。每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的
A, B and lasts answer.
第三个选项中选出最佳选项。听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。边。每段对话或独白读两遍。听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间。
After listening, each question seconds answer.
seconds answer. Do you know what I want to do next summer?
My goal is to climb Black Mountain.
Are you serious?
Black Mountain is too hard to climb.
Don't you need special equipment such as a walking stick, a GPS?
I already asked about it.
I just need good walking boots.
And you're not strong enough to climb such a big mountain.
You're right. I can't do it now.
But I'll go running every weekend.
Next summer, I'll be fit enough to climb the mountain.
Well, good luck.
But as your friend, I still think you should think twice.
Do you know what I want to do next summer?
My goal is to climb Black Mountain.
Are you serious?
Black Mountain is too hard to climb.
Don't you need special equipment such as a walking stick, a GPS?
I already asked about it.
I just need good walking boots.
And you're not strong enough to climb such a big mountain.
You're right. I can't do it now.
But I'll go running every weekend.
Next summer, I'll be fit enough to climb the mountain.
Well, good luck.
But as your friend, I still think you should think twice.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至第十三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Ben, what time does the talent show start?
At three in the afternoon.
Oh, no. I'm in oil painting class until three.
What a pity.
It takes ten minutes to walk from your classroom.
And you are the first one to perform.
Can you tell your teacher you'll leave ten minutes earlier?
Not really. But if you don't mind, I can sing my song at the end of the show instead
of the beginning.
Yeah, that sounds perfect.
We will finish up at about five p.m.
Okay, agreed. Put me down as the last in the talent show, right after the piano
performance. Sure, no problem.
Thanks a lot.
I really appreciate it.
Ben, what time does the talent show start?
At three in the afternoon.
Oh, no. I'm in oil painting class until three.
What a pity.
It takes ten minutes to walk from your classroom.
And you are the first one to perform.
Can you tell your teacher you'll leave ten minutes earlier?
Not really. But if you don't mind, I can sing my song at the end of the show instead
of the beginning.
Yeah, that sounds perfect.
We will finish up at about five p.m.
Okay, agreed. Put me down as the last in the talent show, right after the piano
performance. Sure, no problem.
Thanks a lot.
I really appreciate it.
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至第十三三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
I've been so forgetful lately.
It seems I can't remember anything.
Maybe you should walk to school by a different street.
That might jump -start your brain.
Why would taking different streets to school help my memory?
Sometimes, doing regular activities in a slightly different way can help activate
old memory pathways in our brain, or even build new ones.
Oh, yeah. I have heard that exposure to new sights, sounds, and smells can help the
brain work better.
Right. You could even put some herbs next to your bed, so you wake up to different
smells each morning.
Do you really think doing these things can improve my memory?
Not just your memory, but your ability to learn things, too.
Give it a try.
I've been so forgetful lately.
It seems I can't remember anything.
Maybe you should walk to school by a different street.
That might jump -start your brain.
Why would taking different streets to school help my memory?
Sometimes, doing regular activities in a slightly different way can help activate
old memory pathways in our brain, or even build new ones.
Oh, yeah. I have heard that exposure to new sights, sounds, and smells can help the
brain work better.
Right. You could even put some herbs next to your bed, so you wake up to different
smells each morning.
Do you really think doing these things can improve my memory?
Not just your memory, but your ability to learn things, too.
Give it a Hi, Andy.
嗨。
听下面一段对话。话，回答第十四至第十七四个小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
I've read the story of your parent's firm, My Stay Links, in the newspaper.
It's very successful in the UK,
arranging accommodation for international students to stay with English families.
Yeah, they are very proud of that.
How did they come up with the idea of setting up the firm?
The story goes back to the 1990s.
More and more international students stayed with my family, as my parents
volunteered to help find them suitable schools.
How did you feel having strangers around in your home?
It was great.
We grew up together, really.
After meeting those students and learning about their cultures, I began to consider
going abroad myself, and my parents encouraged me to have a try.
Really? How did you like your experience abroad?
Absolutely amazing.
It was nearly a decade ago.
I made the long journey to China for a summer school program.
I went to live with a local family, who offered me an unforgettable experience.
Three years ago, my parents founded My Stay Links.
I would certainly follow in my family's footsteps and become a homestay host in the
future, even though I'm busy running my own business now.
It's so nice of you to do what your parents are doing.
Hi, Andy. I've read the story of your parents' firm, My Stay Links, in the
newspaper. It's very successful in the UK, arranging accommodation for international
students to stay with English families.
Yeah, they are very proud of that.
How did they come up with the idea of setting up the firm?
The story goes back to the 1990s.
More and more international students stayed with my family, as my parents
volunteered to help find them suitable schools.
How did you feel having strangers around in your home?
It was great.
We grew up together, really.
After meeting those students and learning about their cultures, I began to consider
going abroad myself, and my parents encouraged me to have a try.
Really? How did you like your experience abroad?
Absolutely amazing.
It was nearly a decade ago.
I made the long journey to China for a summer school program.
I went to live with a local family, who offered me an unforgettable experience.
Three years ago, my parents founded My Stay Links.
I would certainly follow in my family's footsteps and become a homestay host in the
future, even though I'm busy running my own business now.
It's so nice of you to do what your parents are doing.
听下面一段独白，回答第十。十八至第二十三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Hi, I'm working on a book about my travels.
I've had the pleasure to see a lot more of the world than anyone my age could
reasonably hope to.
A few years ago, on a vacation trip, I made a video of myself dancing wildly in
foreign places. I put it on the internet.
Some friends started passing it around, and soon millions of people watched it.
I was offered money to continue my travels, and since then I've made two more videos
that include 70 countries on all seven continents.
A lot of people wanted to dance along with me, so I started inviting them to join in
everywhere I went.
Here's what I can report back.
People want to feel connected to each other.
They want to be heard and seen.
And they're curious to hear and see others from places far away.
I share that idea.
It's exactly what drives me to travel.
When I dance with people, I see them smile and laugh.
It makes me truly excited.
Hi, I'm working on a book about my travels.
I've had the pleasure to see a lot more of the world than anyone my age could
reasonably hope to.
A few years ago, on a vacation trip, I made a video of myself dancing wildly in
foreign places. I put it on the internet.
Some friends started passing it around, and soon millions of people watched it.
I was offered money to continue my travels, and since then I've made two more videos
that include 70 countries on all seven continents.
A lot of people wanted to dance along with me, so I started inviting them to join in
everywhere I went.
Here's what I can report back.
People want to feel connected to each other.
They want to be heard and seen.
And they're curious to hear and see others from places far away.
I share that idea.
It's exactly what drives me to travel.
When I dance with people, I see them smile and laugh.
It makes me truly excited.
第二节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you for watching!
You You
听力部分第一次。自考试到此结束。